If you just got a Ninja Creamy or you're
thinking about getting one, let me tell
you everything you need to know about
making the best possible Ninja Creamy.
Hi, I'm Eli aka Fitness Product Finder.
Some people call me the Ninja Creamy
King. Not my words, that's just what
they say. I've made almost 1,000 pints
in the Ninja Creamy. I've developed 150
low calorie, high protein recipes. So, I
think I got you covered. Let's get into
it. Let's start at the base level. So,
making your Ninja Creamy base, the
biggest thing that I see people struggle
with here is the powder kind of clumps
up at the bottom. So, you need to mix it
very thoroughly. I recommend using an
immersion blender or a hand frother,
which is usually what I use. 30 to 60
seconds of mixing will get you right.
Tip number two is use a binding agent.
This also has to do with the base. When
I say binding agent, I mean things like
zantham gum, which is what I use all the
time. Guar gum is another good one. The
most popular is probably Jell-O pudding
mix, which is okay. I think that the
other two are far better. These things
work as a thickening agent. So, they
make the texture much closer to real ice
cream, which is exactly what we want.
Tip number three, moving on to the
freezing process. You need to freeze for
at least 16 hours. Anything less, and it
probably won't be frozen completely
through, and your ice cream will be soft
and probably not like real ice cream
like you want it to be. Tip number four
and moving on to the spinning process. I
highly recommend using the light ice
cream setting. If you didn't know, light
ice cream runs for longer than the ice
cream setting and at a faster rate,
which is better for the low-fat, high
protein recipes that I make and I know a
lot of you make as well. Tip number
five, also to do with the spinning
process, is not to add any milk in
between spins. Now, this can work if you
want a more soft serve blizzard-like
consistency, but if you want real hard
ice cream, adding milk in between spins
is counterintuitive. It makes the ice
cream too soft, and you will probably
get a better result if you just respin
it once, twice, three times, however
many it takes to get that real ice cream
consistency. Tip number six is a big
problem. Ice crystals forming on the
sides of your Ninja Creamy Pints. I can
make a whole video about this if you
guys want me to. Let me know down in the
comments. The best solution to fixing
this problem is running the pine under
hot water for 30 to 60 seconds before
spinning. Or you can leave it out on the
counter for about 10 minutes. That'll
help melt some of the ice crystals on
the sides and help them blend into the
ice cream. Another way to help fix this
is scraping down the sides of the pint
in between spins with a butter knife.
This again will just help that ice blend
into the ice cream rather than just
staying on the sides and just being an
undesirable crunchy factor in your ice
cream. Tip number seven, and arguably
the most important, follow me. If you're
not following me already, what are you
doing? I post ninja creamy recipes,
tips, tricks, ideas, inspiration,
everything you need to know about the
Ninja Creamy every single day.